buildinglink.com 2017-06-06

# BuildingLink.com

Last Updated: March 31, 2017 

Any references to "BuildingLink," "we," "our" or "us" refer to BuildingLink.com, LLC.

BuildingLink respects your privacy as a user of this site. This Privacy Policy explains what personal information we collect from you and how we use that information. This policy also details the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information as well as how you can access and update this information.

This Privacy Policy will be easy to find on the BuildingLink public homepage and on any page where we require information for use of the site.

### What services does the Privacy Policy cover?

This statement applies to all BuildingLink products including the BuildingLink website (www.buildinglink.com), as well as all custom domains created for your building to take you to your BuildingLink site. This Privacy Policy also covers the BuildingLink Blog and all BuildingLink apps and software, including KeyLink (collectively the BuildingLink "Platform").

### Customers and Users

Our "Customer" is typically a legal entity representing a building or property. Customers purchase or license one or more products or services that are part of the Platform.

You are a user of the Platform. BuildingLink collects information from our Customers and users on behalf of our Customers. There are many types of users, and each one has a unique relationship to the information that we collect. Users can include our Customers' employees (building staff, maintenance personnel, managers, etc.), residents (tenants, owners, subtenants, guests, etc.), service providers (outside contractors, local businesses, etc.) and others. Each of these (and generally anyone who has a BuildingLink username and password) is considered a "Registered User". Some users may not be Registered Users, such as a visitor to our public website.

Most Registered Users will be affiliated with one or more BuildingLink Customers (i.e., your buildings). BuildingLink is the custodian of data on behalf of our Customers, with respect to much of the information we collect. Each Customer also determines its own policies regarding information collection, access, sharing and retention. Please contact the Customer if you have any questions regarding their privacy practices.

### The Information we collect

BuildingLink collects both personally identifiable information (such as your name or address) and anonymous information (such as your IP address). Most of this information is provided by our Customers or by you, when you use our Platform.

Some information is obtained through your use of our Platform, for example, when we receive error reports or use cookies (see below).

Finally, we receive some information from other Registered Users. An example would be when a Registered User submits or modifies the information and settings for various non-member 3rd parties, such as family members, roommates, or other people who are relevant to the building's management and who they wish to submit through BuildingLink (e.g. housekeepers, cleaners, caretakers). There may also be personally identifiable information submitted by our Customers about our Registered Users that Registered Users cannot access directly.

The types of information we collect depend on your level of access and engagement with BuildingLink and can include:

  * Contact information such as names, email addresses, mailing addresses, phone numbers
  * Unique identifiers such as usernames, passwords, BuildingLink account numbers
  * Biometric information such as fingerprints
  * Electronic signatures
  * Basic information submitted by you or on your behalf such as maintenance request descriptions, package tracking numbers or amenity reservation details
  * Information uploaded by you such as documents attached to the BuildingLink library
  * If you choose to use sign in services such as Facebook Connect, these services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address.
  * If you choose to use BuildingLink's Payments module, we transmit your payment information via an encrypted connection to our payment processor, Stripe, or such alternate payment processor as we may use now or in the future. We do not store your payment information apart from the payment type and the last four digits of your card number. Stripe processes your payment information in accordance with the [Stripe Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy).
  * Your communications with us, such as your requests for customer support
  * Information about your usage such as IP addresses, browser type, date/time stamp and clickstream data.

### Cookies

We use cookies on this site to provide users with customized and personalized services. Cookies are small amounts of data that are sent to a user's browser from a website and stored on a user's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. This information does not necessarily identify the user, but identifies the user's computer. The cookies used will not collect any personal information like name, address or telephone number. 

## Our use of cookies and other tracking technologies

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" directory. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site will be limited.

### Web Beacons / GIFs

Third party tracking technology companies employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

### Analytics / Log Files

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

### 3rd Party Tracking

The use of tracking technologies by our service providers, technology partners or other 3rd party assets (such as social media widgets and plug-ins) on the site is not covered by our privacy policy. These 3rd parties may use cookies, clear gifs, images, and scripts to help them better manage their content on our site. We do not have access or control over these technologies. We do not tie the information gathered to our Customers' or Users' personally identifiable information.

### How we use the information

For users of our platform, we use the information we receive to:

  * Provide the services our Customer requested
  * Notify you of activity related to your account, such as when a package is delivered to the property for you
  * Administer your account
  * Respond to customer service and support requests
  * Create and provide better and improved products and services based on your use of the site and your feedback
  * List you in our member directory made available only to other members of your building
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Send you our newsletter, which you may opt out of at any time

For visitors requesting information about our products and services from one of our websites, we use the information we receive to:

  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Send you our newsletter, which you may opt out of at any time

If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

### Service Providers

We share your personal information with your consent or as necessary to complete any transaction or provide any product you have requested or authorized. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us deliver our services such as processing payments (Stripe), hosting applications or fulfilling other functions of the website. These third-party service providers are limited to accessing or using this information solely for the purposes of providing services to us and to you and must provide reasonable assurances that they will appropriately safeguard all information. For example, we transfer anonymous phone numbers to our communications provider Twilio, which completes calls and text messages for our Emergency Broadcast module. You can view Twilio’s Privacy Policy [here](https://www.twilio.com/legal/privacy).

For our E.U. users: We participate in the E.U.-U.S. Privacy Shield (see statement below), and this privacy policy indicates our compliance with the Principles of the Privacy Shield. Accordingly, BuildingLink is responsible for the processing of information we receive pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfer to a third party acting on our behalf (e.g. a service provider). It is our responsibility to ensure that any service providers we use also adhere to the Principles.

### Aggregated Information

Your personal information is neither sold nor rented to third parties without your express permission. We do retain the right to share non-identifying aggregated demographic and/or statistical information with partners, advertisers and sponsors.

We may use non-identifying and aggregate information to improve your experience on the website and to share with partners, advertisers and sponsors. For example, any personal information will remain with us, however, your visit may be counted to demonstrate the number of visitors to a particular page or area of the site.

### Links to Third Party Sites

Our platform includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of BuildingLink. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

### Legal Disclaimer

We may disclose your personal information:

  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * If BuildingLink is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information

BuildingLink will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Customers for as long as needed to provide services and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

### User Access and Choice

You may access, correct, update, amend or remove certain personally identifiable information by making the change on your user account settings page, by requesting that your property manager (or other program administrator) make such change on your behalf, by emailing our customer support team at [support@buildinglink.com](mailto:support@buildinglink.com), or calling +1-877-501-7117. If you no longer require our service, or wish to request your personal information be deleted/removed, please contact us using the aforementioned direct methods. Termination of service proceedings are conducted offline and are subject to approval by our Customer, if you are a resident or staff user. We will respond to your request within thirty (30) days.

### Our commitment to children's privacy

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

### The EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

BuildingLink.com complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information from the European Union. BuildingLink.com has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, and to view our certification, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov.](http://www.privacyshield.gov/)

For questions, comments, complaints, access requests or other issues relating to the Privacy Shield or our Privacy Policy, please email [support@buildinglink.com](mailto:support@buildinglink.com) or call +1-877-501-7117. For any issues that cannot be resolved through BuildingLink.com directly, you may contact JAMS at <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. If your concerns are still not addressed by JAMS, you may be entitled to a binding arbitration under the Privacy Shield Principles.

The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has jurisdiction over BuildingLink.com's compliance with the Privacy Shield.

### Personal Information Protection and Electronic Data Act (“PIPEDA”)

For our Canadian Customers, BuildingLink shall act in accordance with the privacy provisions contained in the PIPEDA. 

### Changes to this policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this page prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. The most recent version of this Privacy Policy supersedes all other versions.

### Contact Us
